Mss.B.F867
American Philosophical Society
Persifor Frazer papers, 1882-1906
Mss.B.F867
American Philosophical Society
1.0 Linear feet c. 220 items in 2 boxes
c. 220 items.
The letters to Persifor Frazer cover primarily matters related to geology and mineralogy. A portion of the correspondence, principally from British scientists, concerns the 1884 meeting in Philadelphia of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (B F867).
Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
Box 1
Scope and Contents note
The collection contains 213 manuscript items, 4 pamphlets, 1 broadside, 6 newspaper clippings and 1 calling card. They are dated between 1882 and 1906. Most of the material is in English, but there are also a few items in French and German. A typed table of contents is included in the box.
Many of the manuscript letters (156) are correspondence from various persons, mostly British, to Persifor Frazer, pertaining to the 1884 meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, which was held in Philadelphia. All were written between June and September of 1884.
A good number of the items reflect Frazer’s interest in mineralogy and geology. They include a sizeable body of letters from Thomas Sterry Hunt, as well as the letters by James Hall and Joseph Leidy. They concern the examination of specimens, relevant publications, and the correspondents’ research. The letters by James Geikie tend to focus on current events and personal matters; they often have a light tone (as in the letter of October 14, 1885, which begins “My dear Chieftain” and goes on to tell Frazer about Geikie’s trip to the Highlands, where he indulged “in bagpipe music, whiskey, venison, and flirtations with the ladies”).
The collection also includes several letters by Ernst Heinrich Haeckel, all in German. Several of them refer to Haeckel’s book Weltraethsel. Also included is a letter in which Haeckel informs Frazer of his inability to attend the celebrations in honor of the 200th anniversary of Franklin’s birthday, held at the APS in 1906.
Related Archival Materials note
For papers of his father John Fries Frazer, see B F865. For papers of his grandfather Robert Frazer, see B F868.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
C. 150 items were purchased and accessioned, 1957 (1957 731ms). Other accession numbers and dates: 1957 156ms (2 items; formerly B F867.1; B F867.2); 1958 2254ms (1 item; formerly B F867.3); 1958 2255ms (1 item; formerly B F867.4); 1958 2256ms (1 item; formerly B F867.5); 1958 2257ms (1 item; formerly B F867.6); 1958 2258ms (1 item; formerly B F867.7); 1958 2259ms (1 item; formerly B F867.8); 1958 2260ms; (48 items; Letters from various persons, 1883-1885; formerly B F867.9).
Biographical/Historical note
Persifor Frazer (1844–1909, APS 1872) was a geologist and handwriting expert. He participated in geological surveys for the United States and for Pennsylvania and, after 1870, held the chair in chemistry at the University of Pennsylvania. He also published a manual on handwriting and, as a specialist in the identification of forged documents, served as an expert witness in several high profile trials. Persifor Frazer, also known as Persifor, Jr., was the only son of the Philadelphia scientist and educator John Fries Frazer (1812–1872, APS 1842) and his wife Charlotte Cave Frazer. He attended private schools before enrolling at the University of Pennsylvania, receiving his B.A. in 1862.
Frazer enlisted in the Union Army at the beginning of the Civil War. He served in the United States Coast Survey and was assigned to a South Atlantic squadron under Samuel F. DuPont (1803-1865, APS 1862). Later, he volunteered to fight in the Gettysburg campaign; and in 1864 became the acting ensign attached to the Mississippi Squadron. In 1865, after his honorable discharge, Frazer was granted a semi-honorary A.M. degree from the University of Pennsylvania.
Frazer studied chemistry in Philadelphia for six months before enrolling in the Royal Saxon School of Mines in Freiburg, Germany. He remained there for three years, focusing on the study of mineralogy and related subjects. In 1869 he was selected to serve as mineralogist and metallurgist to the United States Geological Survey, led by Ferdinand V. Hayden. In this capacity, he completed a report on Mining and Mineralogy of Colorado and Wyoming. In 1870 he became an instructor at the University of Pennsylvania; the next year he succeeded his father as Professor of Chemistry.
In 1874 Frazer resigned from his faculty position to join the Second Geological Survey of Pennsylvania, under the leadership of J. Peter Lesley (1819-1903, APS 1856). During his eight years with the Survey, he published a highly regarded report primarily on the southeastern counties of the state. In 1881 Frazer was the General Manager of the Central Virginia Iron Company. He was a founder of the American Geologist which he edited from 1888 to 1905. In 1889 he accepted an appointment as Professor of Chemistry of the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society. Two years later he became the Chair of Chemistry at the Franklin Institute. Frazer was a member of the American committee at the International Congress of Geologists three times: in Berlin (1885), London (1888), and St. Petersburg (1897). He also worked as a consulting metallurgist, geologist and mining engineer. In this capacity he traveled to different places in North America and abroad.
In later years, Frazer turned his attention to the study of handwriting, and soon became a widely respected expert in the field. In the course of his studies, he visited Aphonse Bertillon, the eminent French police officer and biometrics researcher. In 1894 Frazer published the highly regarded book A Manual for the Study of Documents (later re-titled Bibliotics; or, the Study of Documents …), which was intended to assist in the detection of forged handwriting. His main contribution to the field consisted in his recognition that fine tremors in handwriting could be detected under a microscope, and that these tremors were linked to the nerve state of the writer. A close comparison of tremors in different writing samples could help detect forgeries. Frazer’s expertise soon attracted the attention of lawyers. He was asked to serve as an expert witness in several high-profile trials, such as the 1899 murder trial of Roland B. Molineux of New York City. Based on his experiences in these trials, including his dismissal from a case for his refusal to swear to his belief in the existence of God, Frazer wrote the article "Expert Testimony: Its Uses and Abuses" (1902). In it he attacked the ways in which expert witnesses were generally treated by judges on the bench. The City of Philadelphia awarded him the John Scott Medal in 1906 for his invention of the colorimeter which measured the intensity and color value of ink in handwriting.
Frazer's scholarly output numbered around 300 titles. He also belonged to numerous learned and patriotic organizations. He was a founder of the Society of American Geologists and the Franklin Institute Journal. Other affiliations include, but are not limited to, the Academy of Natural Sciences, the Society of American Geologists, the Military Order of the Loyal Legion, the General and Pennsylvania Society of Sons of the Revolution, the Society of the War of 1812, the Society of Colonial Wars of Pennsylvania, the British Association for the Advancement of Science, the New York Academy of Science, and the Reichsanstalt of Vienna. He became a member of the American Philosophical Society in 1872, serving as its secretary from 1896 to 1898.
Persifor Frazer was married to Isabella Nevins Whelen. They had four children, three of whom lived to adulthood. He died on April 7, 1909, the day that the Pennsylvania State Senate passed a bill that allowed agnostics to testify as competent witnesses on affirmation.
American Association for the Advancement of Science.; Science -- Societies, etc.; Scientists -- Great Britain.
- Papers
  - Botanical memorandum, June 28, 1882; B F867.2; 5-1/4x8-1/4; Bertrand, Charles Eugène, 1851-1917
    Scope and Contents note
    A.D.S. 1p. Formerly B F867.2.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    1957 156ms
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 5, 1882; B F867.1; 8-1/4x5-1/4; stamped env.; Bertrand, Charles Eugéne, 1851-1917
    Lille, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Sends his portrait. Formerly B F867.1.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, February 8, 1883; B F867.9; 5-1/2x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 3p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Congratulates him on his thesis. Concerning geology. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Cablegram to [Persifor] Frazer, Philadelphia, February 23, 1883; B F867.9; 5x8; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    London, D. 1p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Tells him to stop his paper. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 30, 1883; B F867.9; 7x4-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning geology of New York. Asks that trousers he left behind be forwarded to him. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, May 16, 1883; B F867.9; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 6p. Enc. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Geology of New York. Geological matters. Concerning Geikie. For enclosure, see: Hunt to P.Frazer; May 16, [1883]. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, May 16, [1883]; B F867.9; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. (see P. Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the meetings of the B.A.A.S. and the A.A.A.S. Concerning natural water. Enclosed originally in: same to same; May 16, 1883. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 23, 1883; B F867.9; 9-3/4x6; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P. Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the meeting of the American and British geologists. Concerning Geikie. Friendly letter. Concerning the Canadian royal society. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, July 6, 1883; B F867.9; 5-1/2x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L. 4p. Incomplete. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning geology. Concerning the A.A.A.S. Concerning Geikie. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 1, 1883; B F867.9; 5-1/2x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Geological news. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 18, 1883; B F867.9; 11x8-1/2; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning slates and the analysis of fossils on them. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor Frazer], September 22, 1883; B F867.9; 9-1/2x6; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning fossils. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, November 5, [1883]; B F867.9; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons. 1883-1885.) Geological matters for Frazer's forthcoming publication. Concerning the A.A.A.S. and B.A.A.S. meetings. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to F[rederick] W[ard] Putnam, December 3, 1883; B F867.9; 7-3/4x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the forthcoming meeting of the A.A.A.S. Refers to P.Frazer, et al. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, January 16, 1884; B F867.9; 9-1/2x6; Hall, James, 1811-1898
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, January 17, 1884; B F867.9; 9-1/2x6; Hall, James, 1811-1898
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, January 30, 1884; B F867.9; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 6p. (see P. Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Geology. Concerning the forthcoming meeting of the A.A.A.S. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, February 28, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 8p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the forthcoming A. A. A. S.. meeting and the B.A.A.S.members who may attend. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 2, 1884; B F867.9; 8x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 6p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the forthcoming meeting of the A.A.A.S. and the B.A.A.S. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 3, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 7p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the invitation from the A.A.A.S. to the B.A.A.S. for the forthcoming meeting. Concerning geology. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 6, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 7p. (see P.Frazer Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the A.A.A.S.-B.A.A.S.meeting in Philadelphia. Concerning Pennsylvania geology. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, March 25, 1884; B F867.9; 8x5; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    A.L.S. 1p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning fossil diatoms. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 27, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Will see him shortly. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 27, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the A.A.A.S.-B.A.A.S.meeting and plans for it. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 6, [1884]; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) His plans for the next few days. Hopes to help plan the A.A.A.S.-B.A.A.S. meetings. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 11, 1884; B F867.9; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the Canadian geological survey. Friendly letter. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 17, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Will be in Philadelphia this week-end. Concerning his business there. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, May 1, 1884; B F867.9; 3x5; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning a mastodon tusk. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, May 24, 1884; Foster, Le Neve
    Asks about Frazer's planned excursion to Colorado.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 7, 1884; Beverley, Michael
    Plans to attend meetin of the American Association.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 7, 1884; Letter, 2 calling cards.; Horniman, Frederick John
    Scoep and Contents note
    Plans to attend American Association meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 7, 1884; Martin, John B.
    Regarding a paragraph that appears in the "Times" today. Hopes to be able to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 9, 1884; Salt, Shirley H.
    Hopes to be able to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 12, 1884; Perry, A.J.
    Plans to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 13, 1884; Ransom, Edwin
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 13, 1884; Rayleigh, Clara
    She and her two sons will attend the meeting. Her son Lord Rayleigh is president of the British Association.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 14, 1884; Butcher, W. Draur
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 14, 1884; Hotblacu, George S.
    Will attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 15, 1884; Stone, W. H. (William Henry), 1830-1891
    Hopes to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 16, 1884; B F867.9; 3x5; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    Wallingford, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Wants to add nothing to the "Com[mittee] on Nominations". Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 16, 1884; Alger, W.H.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 16, 1884; Burton, Frederick M.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 16, 1884; Ramsay, William, 1852-1916
    Plans to attend meeting with his wife.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 17, 1884; Letter and calling card.; Cooke, Conrad William, 1843-1926
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 17, 1884; McClure, J. H. (John H.)
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 17, 1884; Moseley, H.N.
    Plans to attend meeting with his wife. Dr. E.B. Tylor and wife will also attend.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 17, 1884; Weldon, Walter, 1832-1885
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 18, 1884; David, A.J.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 18, 1884; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    He and James Grant Wilson plan to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 19, 1884; Woodcock, T.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 19, 1884; Wright, Arthur
    He and the Reverend B. Wright plan to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 20, 1884; Schuster, Arthur, Sir, 1851-1934
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 21, 1884; Thompson, Isaac Grant
    Plans to attend meeting. Will be accompanied by Prof. J.O. Lodge and Dr. Baker.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 21, 1884; Williams, E. Starbuck
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 22, 1884; B F867.9; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P. Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Plans to attend the unveiling of the B.Silliman statue at Yale. Accepts his invitation to stay during Sept. with the Frazers. News of friends and scientists. Refers to Hall. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 22, 1884; Foster, Le Neve
    Plans to attend meeting. Inquires about Frazer's planned excursion.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 22, 1884; Letter and calling card.; Spanton, W. Dunnett
    he and Dr. J.T. Arlidge plan to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 23, 1884; Fox, Charles
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 24, 1884; Wells, Edward
    Is requesting list of subjects to be discussed at meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 25, 1884; Spruce, Samuel
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 28, 1884; Cunningham, D.J.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 30, 1884; Baynes, Robert E.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 30, 1884; Dowson, J. Emerson
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 30, 1884; Pearson, Helen E.
    She and Miss Hargreaves plan to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 1, 1884; Browne, Walter R.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 1, 1884; Liveing, G. D. (George Downing), 1827-1924
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 2, 1884; Letter and calling card.; Nutt, Lilian M.
    Hopes to be able to attend meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 3, 1884; Briggs, Arthur
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 3, 1884; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Plans to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 3, 1884; Rigg, Arthur
    Plans to attend the meeting (but will not be there on the 4th).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 4, 1884; Pullar, Robert
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 7, 1884; Barker, Arthur A.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 8, 1884; Westlake, Ernest, 1855-1922
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 9, 1884; Ommanney, Erasmus
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 10, 1884; B F867.9; 8x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the B.A.A.S. Concerning geology. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 10, 1884; Shadwell, John Lancelot
    Plans to attend the meeting along with his brother.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 14, 1884; Brown, John
    Regrets that he will most likely miss the Philadelphia meeting, instead planning to visit the Rocky Mountains after the Montreal meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 14, 1884; Peace, G. H.
    Plans to attend the meeting; expresses interest in visiting the coal districts.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 14, 1884; Robertson, Geo[rge] H.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 15, 1884; Gwyther, R. F.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 16, 1884; Bevan, J. O. (James Oliver)
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 16, 1884; Jackson, Alfred H.
    Hopes to attend the meeting along with his brother, Harold Jackson; discusses travel plans and hopes that the Rocky Mountain trip and Philadelphia are not mutually exclusive.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 16, 1884; Whittall, J.
    Whittall, Secretary of the Statistical Society, writing to inform Frazer that Major Patrick G. Craigie and Mr. John B. Martin have been appointed as delegates to the Philadelphia meeting, and Martin has unofficially confirmed he plans to attend.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 17, 1884; Horniman, Frederick John
    Plans to attend the meeting; informs Frazer of travel plans. 2 items: letter and calling card.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 18, 1884; Blanford, William Thomas, 1832-1905
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 18, 1884; Woodall, John W.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 19, 1884; Cooke, Conrad William, 1843-1926
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 19, 1884; Godson, Alfred
    Plans to attend the meeting, along with Taylor Whitehead and his son.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 19, 1884; Westwood Oliver, J. A.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 19, 1884; Wrightson, Thomas
    Plans to attend the meeting. 2 items: letter and calling card with handwritten information.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 20, 1884; Hayward, Robert B.
    Regretfully declines invitation, but his son and daughter will attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 21, 1884; Browne, Walter
    Regrets he will not be in attendance.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 21, 1884; Cotterill, Professor
    Hopes to attend the meeting; will not be accompanied by friends or family. (Written in the third person--on behalf of James H. Cotterill?)
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 21, 1884; Hoffmann, G. M.
    Handwritten note on the letterhead of Alfred R. C. Selwyn of the Geological & Natural History Survey, Dept. of the Interior, Canada.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 22, 1884; Arnold, Edward M.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 22, 1884; Beverley, Michael
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 22, 1884; Martin, John B.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 22, 1884; Marshall, A. Milnes
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 22, 1884; Reynolds, A. H.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 22, 1884; Savery, G. M.
    Plans to attend the meeting, accompanied by his sister-in-law and her uncle.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 23, 1884; Readman, J. B.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 25, 1884; Jackson, M.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 25, 1884; Ross, A.
    Discussion of possible attendees.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 26, 1884; Dowson, J. Emerson
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 26, 1884; B F867.9; 9-1/2x6; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Northampton, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Friendly letter. Plans to stay elsewhere during the A.A.A.S.meeting in Philadelphia. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 28, 1884; B F867.9; 8x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892